





# **TAMÁS BARTOS**

### **SUMMARY**

Result-driven software engineer with 8+ years of experience in strategic problem solving and arcthitecture planning. Eager to learn new technologies and always strive for excellence. Worked alongside product managers to build multiple microservice based application using services infrastructure as code.

#### **STRENGTHS**



Problem solving



Collaboration



്പ് Leadership

#### **SKILLS**

AWS

Typescript - NodeJS - React Python - Java - PHP DynamoDB - MongoDB - PSQL Event Driven microservice design

#### **EDUCATION**

2011 - 2017 Szeged, Hungary Economic Informatics | Bachelor Degree University of Szeged

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Senior Software Engineer Joyn GmbH

11/2021 – present, Münich, Germany

- Designed and documented multiple architecture plans. coordinating cross-team collaboration to ensure smooth implementation and delivery.
- Took end-to-end ownership of service design, including database schema design and inter-service communication patterns to ensure consistency, scalability, and maintainability.
- Facilitated Scrum-based development by translating finalized architecture plans into detailed Jira tickets for multiple development teams.
- Developed numerous microservices using Python and TypeScript (Node.js) following an event-driven architecture, utilizing Kafka, AWS SQS, and SNS.
- Pioneered the adoption of AWS CDK and standardized ESLint configurations, promoting best practices and maintainability across
- Acted as a trusted point of contact and "go-to" person for technical challenges and urgent issues, frequently consulted by peers and stakeholders during critical situations.

## **Associate Lead Software Engineer** Mentor Graphics (Siemens Business)

11/2019 - 11/2021, Budapest, Hungary

- Investigated modern web and cloud technologies, recommending them for new projects or refactors for teams primarily based in the USA, India, Hungary, and the UK.
- Developed numerous microservice-based web applications using Docker solutions with AWS and Node.js.
- Created a web application with React to manage large SVGs.
- Supported and coordinated the migration of a large legacy Java application to AWS.

## Senior software engineer **Epam Systems**

12/2018 - 11/2019, Szeged, Hungary

- Developed the backend for a warehouse monitoring web page using AWS and Node.js within a 10+ member team following Scrum methodology.
- Created a custom Lambda function for comprehensive authentication and authorization management in the web application.
- Mentored junior colleagues.

## Junior to Lead software engineer Gremon Systems Zrt.

08/2016 - 12/2018, Szeged, Hungary

- Developed a workflow monitoring system for gardeners and greenhouses using Java, Android, and Angular.
- Developed an irrigation system for greenhouses using PHP, React, and AWS.
- Responsible for sprint planning and coordinating juniors and outsourced seniors on development tasks.